

OFTWARE ENGINEER · DATA SC

Dubai - UAE
□+971 58 575 7397 | ■ joorgemelo@gmail.com | ♠ jorgeribeiro.github.io | □ jorgeribeiro | □ joorgeribeeiro

"Choose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life."

Summary.

Current Software Engineer at Privilee. I have worked for the past 6 years as a Full Stack Developer with special interest in backend challenges. The goal of my life is to keep learning new technologies and tools to create and enhance products to improve people's lives. My daily routine is to be an engineer in full time, thinking solutions to optimize workflows and make suggestions to contribute to people's work. Last but not least, always an open-source lover.

Work Experience _

Privilee Dubai - UAE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov. 2019 - PRESENT

- Improvements to the current API that is used to serve content to the website, management system and mobile app.
- · Development of a new management system to be used by the several departments in the company.
- Development of a new API using data primarily from NoSQL databases.
- The technologies used to power the projects are: PHP (Zend), Framework 7, Vue.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase and Docker.

Westwing Brazil Brazil

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Development of a new e-commerce system to sell products and integrate it to the current one.
- Debugging all the services included in the system in order to analyse its flows.
- The project is built with Docker, Memcached, RabbitMQ, Solr and Dynamo. Based on PHP, Javascript and MySQL.
- My team works in an agile environment, and we use Jira to define stories and sprints.

Equatorial Energia Group

Brazil

DATA SCIENTIST Mar. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Automating routines, reports and dashboards with Power BI for the Legal Department.
- · Analysing data from internal databases to help attorneys at their decision making.
- Applying Machine Learning techniques (R-Script) to interpret customer behavior.
- Development of applications to improve Tax and Corporate Law workflows and persist their data for further analysis.

Senior Team Projects and Solutions

Brazi

Jan. 2018 - Feb. 2019

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

• Development of web applications to the Maranhão Audit Court using Java, EJB, ZK Framework and PostgreSQL.

• Refactored an application called Segurança (Security) that manages employees' user accounts and provides access to internal systems, along with two other team members.

Education

UFMA (Federal University of Maranhão)

Brazil

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2018

Carroll University Wisconsin - USA Wisconsin - USA

Exchange in Computer Science Aug. 2015 - May. 2016

Projects_

Heart Disease Classifier

PYTHON, PANDAS, SKLEARN, FLASK, ANGULAR

- Classification of heart disease based on symptoms and personal features. It uses a heart disease dataset from the UCI Machine Learning Repository.
- Its source code and description can be found at https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/heart-disease-classifier.

Computer Science Planner

LARAVEL, BULMA, SQLITE

- This application helps Computer Science Students from UFMA in the selection of classes in each semester, in order to complete the required hours in less time.
- Source code and instructions: https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/planejador-cp-ufma.

Meta learning applied to the Problem of Facial Expression Recognition

PYTHON, TENSORFLOW, NEURAL NETWORKS, META LEARNING

- Undergraduate thesis developed to become a Computer Scientist bachelor.
- It uses Convolutional Neural Networks and three datasets to learn emotions from human faces.
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Source code and docs can be found at https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/meta-learning-facial-expression-recognition}.$

Github Web Scraper

PYTHON, BEAUTIFULSOUP, REQUESTS, PIPENV

- Crawler that gather information about files and sizes of any public Github repository. It creates a tree of files and folders and provides information about percentage of lines of code and bytes.
- Its source code and description can be found at https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/github-web-scraper.